BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 3) 6178/003
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 3)
1944- 1977
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
United States Department of Labor
Bureau of Labor Statistics (BLS)
6178/003
16.5 cubic feet
16.5 linear ft.
Records (documents), collective labor agreements.
5833596
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, June 28, 2005
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, October 18, 2016
Biographical / Historical
The US Bureau of Labor Statistics (BLS) was established in 1884 to collect information about employment and labor in the United States. As mandated by the 1947 Taft-Hartley Act, the BLS was formally tasked with responsibility for soliciting, collecting, and analyzing collective bargaining agreements (CBAs) from public and private establishments, and making the agreements publicly available. In the early 1980s, this was function was limited to union contracts made with employers of 1000 or more employees.
In 2002, the National Archives and Records Administration authorized the BLS to donate inactive, non-confidential agreements which were 5 years or more past their expiration date to the Kheel Center where they would be preserved and made available to the public. The Office of Labor-Management Services took over responsibility for collecting and analyzing CBAs in 2011, and continues this donor relationship with the Kheel Center.
Scope and Contents
The US Department of Labor Historical Collective Bargaining Agreements Collection, 6178, is made up of 21 series of expired public- and private-sector collective bargaining agreements dating from 1887 to 2003 and totals 685 linear feet plus 10 CDs of digitized documents and 320 reels of microfilm. In addition to the CBAs, a small volume of related documents such as union constitutions, pension and health plans submitted to the BLS, are also available.
Selected collective bargaining agreements from this collection were digitized with generous funding from the National Historic Publications and Records Commission (NHPRC), and the National Science Foundation (NSF). Because documents other than collective bargaining agreements were also collected and preserved here by the US Department of Labor, a folder containing material that has been digitized, may also contain material which has not been digitized such as constitutions, bylaws, working rules, life insurance plans, or other organizational documents. For access to non-digitized material, contact Kheel Center staff.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6178/001: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 1) 6178/002: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 2) 6178/004: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 4) 6178/006: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 6) 6178/007: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 7) 6178/008: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 8) 6178/009: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 9) 6178/010: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 10) 6178/011: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 11) 6178/012: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 12) 6178/013: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 13) 6178/014: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 14) 6178/015: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 15) 6178/016: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 16) 6178/017: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 17) 6178/018: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 18) 6178/019: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 19) 6178/020: OLMS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 20) 6178/021(d): BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 21) Digital 6178/022 mf: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 22) on Microfilm 6178/023: OLMS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 23)
Arrangement
Series I: Industry Code #11, Agriculture, Forestry, Fishing and Hunting
Series II: Industry Code #21, Mining, Quarrying, and Oil and Gas Extraction
Series III: Industry Code #22, Utilities
Series IV: Industry Code #23, Construction
Series V: Industry Code #31, Manufacturing
Series VI: Industry Code #32, Manufacturing
Series VII: Industry Code #33, Manufacturing
Series VIII: Industry Code #42, Wholesale Trade
Series IX: Industry Code #44, Retail Trade
Series X: Industry Code #45, Retail Trade
Series XI: Industry Code #48, Transportation and Warehousing
Series XII: Industry Code #49, Transportation and Warehousing
Series XIII: Industry Code #51, Information
Series XIV: Industry Code #52, Finance and Insurance
Series XV: Industry Code #54, Professional, Scientific, and Technical Services
Series XVI: Industry Code #56, Administrative and Support and Waste Management and Remediation Services
Series XVII: Code #62, Health Care and Social Assistance
Series XVIII: Code #71, Arts, Entertainment, and Recreation
Series XIX: Code #72, Accommodation and Food Services
Series XX: Code #81, Other Services (except Public Administration)
Collective labor agreements -- Meat industry -- United States.; Collective labor agreements -- Rubber industry workers z United States; Collective labor agreements -- Paper industry -- United States.; Collective labor agreements -- Electric industry -- United States.; Collective labor agreements -- Construction industry -- United States.; Collective labor agreements -- Clothing trade -- United States.; Collective labor agreements -- Shiopbuilding industry -- United States.; Collective labor agreements -- Iron industry -- United States.; Collective labor agreements -- Automobile industry -- United States.; Collective labor agreements -- Machinery industry -- United States.; Collective labor agreements -- Retail trade -- United States.; Collective labor agreements -- Stevedores -- United States.; United States. Department of Labor.; United States. Bureau of Labor Statistics.; United States. Bureau of Labor Statistics -- Archives; Amalgamated Meat Cutters and Butcher Workmen of North America; International Brotherhood of Boiler Makers, Iron Ship Builders, and Helpers of America -- Archives; International Brotherhood of Pulp, Sulphite, and Paper Mill Workers. b Local 150 -- Archives; United Steelworkers of America; Communication Workers Union -- Archives; International Union, United Automobile, Aircraft, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America -- Archives; United Rubber, Cork, Linoleum, and Plastic Workers of America; International Union, United Automobile, Aerospace, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America -- Archives; International Union of Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers -- Archives; International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers -- Archives; International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers -- Archives; United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America -- Archives; Industrial Union of Marine and Shipbuilding Workers of America -- Archives; International Brotherhood of Teamsters -- Archives; United Association of Journeymen Plumbers and Steam Fitters of the United States and Canada -- Archives; Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union; Amalgamated Association of Street, Electric Railway and Motor Coach Employees of America -- Archives; International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America -- Archives; Hotel & Restaurant Employees and Bartenders International Union -- Archives; International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employees and Moving Picture Machine Operators of the United States and Canada -- Archives; United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry -- Archives; Laborers' International Union of North America -- Archives; International Longshoremen's Association; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union -- Archives; Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union -- Archives
5833596
- Series I: Industry Code #11, Agriculture, Forestry, Fishing and Hunting
  - Code no.6320: Food Employers' Labor Relations, Inc. and International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America Locals 929, 470, 676, 1963-1970 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Series II: Industry Code #21, Mining, Quarrying, and Oil and Gas Extraction
  - Code no.8319: Hanna Mining Company and United Steelworkers of America, 1962-1971 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Code no.6086: Panhandle Eastern Pipe Line Company and Oil, Chemical, and Atomic Workers International Union, 1957-1976 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Series III: Industry Code #22, Utilities
  - Code no.6012: Duquesne Light Company and Allegheny County Steam Heating Company and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Locals 140, 142, 144, 147, 148, 1968-1973 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Code no.6035: Union Electric Company and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Local 1455, 1963-1973 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Code no.6038: Utah Power and Light Company and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Local 57, 1967-1975 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Code no.6050: Pacific Lighting Service Company and Southern California Gas Company and International Chemical Workers Union, Utility Workers Union of America, 1971-1974 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Code no.6077: San Diego Gas and Electric Company and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 465, 1966-1971 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Code no.6062: Gulf States Utilities Company and Independent Electrical Workers Union, 1968-1970 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Code no.6062: Gulf States Utilities Company and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 2286, 1970-1972 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Code no.6065: Long Island Lighting Company and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 1049, 1967-1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Code no.6066: Long Island Lighting Company and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 1381, 1967-1972 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Code no.6067: Louisville Gas and Electric Company and Independent Protective Association of Utility Workers, 1967-1972 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Code no.6069: Northern Indiana Public Service Company and International Union of District 50, UMWA, 1968-1971 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Code no.6070: New York State Electric and Gas Corporation and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Locals 249, 945, 951, 961, 966, 992, 994, 1111, 1125, 1126, 1143, System Council U-7, Production and Clerical, 1967-1973 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Code no.6072: Pacific Gas and Electric Company and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 1245, 1960-1976 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Scope and Contents
    1960-1970, 1974-1976
  - Code no.6073: Pacific Gas and Electric Company and Engineers and Scientists of California, 1960-1972 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Code no.6075: Public Service Co. of Colorado and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Locals 111, 925, 1436, 1946- 1968 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Code no.6076: Public Service Electric and Gas Company and Utility Co-Workers' Association, 1969-1973 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Code no.6078: Southwestern Public Service Company and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 602, 1961-1969 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Code no.6084: Northern Illinois Gas Company and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Locals 1519, 1878, 1879, 1880, 1881, 1882, 1887, 1961-1971 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Code no.6088: Public Service Electric and Gas Company and United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry Local 274, Public Utility Construction and Gas Appliance Workers of the State of New Jersey, 1963-1973 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Code no.6089: Central Hudson Gas and Electric Corporation and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Locals 320 and 2218, AFL, 1965-1973 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Code no.6000: Alabama Power Company and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Locals 345, 833, 904, 391, 801, 841, 1053, 796, 1967-1972 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Code no.6002: Arkansas Power and Light Company and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Locals 647, 1703, 750, 1967- 1970 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Code no.6005: Boston Edison Company, Production and Maintenance Unit and Utility Workers Union of America Local 369, 1969- 1973 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Code no.6007: Cleveland Electric Illuminating Company and Utility Workers Union of America Local 270, 1968-1971 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Code no.6008: Commonwealth Edison Company and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Locals 1441, 1459, 1460, 1461, 1469, 1479, 1515, 1971-1973 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Code no.6011: Commonwealth Edison Company and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Locals 1540, 1539, 1540, 1557, 1969- 1973 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Code no.6015: Georgia Power Company and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Local 84, 1965-1973 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Code no.6016: Houston Lighting and Power Company and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Local 66, 1970-1972 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Code no.6019: Kansas Power and Light Company and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 304, 1970-1974 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Code no.6024: Pennsylvania Electric Company and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Locals 30, 459, 521, 1124, 1138, 1265, 1344, 1968-1972 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Code no.6027: Public Service Electric and Gas Company, Electric Operating Dept. and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Locals 853, 1134, 1320, 1329, 1330, 1335, 1338, 1345, 1350, 1355, 1368, 1673, 1971-1973 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Code no.6028: Public Service Company of Indiana, Inc. and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 1393, 1969- 1973 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Code no.6034: Union Electric Company and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Locals 309, 649, 1439, 1963-1973 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Code no.6040: Wisconsin Electric Power Company and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 2150, 1971-1973 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Code no.6041: Wisconsin Electric Power Company and United Association of Office, Sales, and Technical Employees, Local Division 2, 1970- 1974 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Code no.6042: Boston Gas Company and International Union of District 50, Locals 12003 and 12118, 1970-1973 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Code no.6403: Brooklyn Union Gas Company and Transport Workers Union of America Local 101, Utility Division, 1971-1973 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Code no.6044: East Ohio Gas Company and Service Employees' International Union Local 555, Natural Gas Workers Union, 1969- 1973 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Code no.6045: Consolidated Gas Supply Corporation and Allegheny Mountain Gas Workers' Union, 1965-1972 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Code no.6049: The Peoples Natural Gas Company and Gas Employees' Independent Union, 1960-1964 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Code no.6054: Washington Gas Light Company and International Union of Gas Workers, 1970-1974 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Code no.6055: Cincinnati Gas and Electric Company, the Union Light, Heat, and Power Company and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 1347, 1961-1970 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Code no.6056: Cincinnati Gas and Electric Company, the Union Light, Heat, and Power Company and Independent Utilities Union, 1967- 1971 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Code no.6057: Connecticut Light and Power Company and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Locals 420, 753, 1045, 1175, 1226, 1373, 1817, 1967-1973 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Code no.6058: Consolidated Edison Company of New York, Inc. and Utility Workers of America, Local Union No. 1-2, 1968-1973 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Code no.6059: Consumers Power Company and Utility Workers of America, 1969-1971 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Code no.6061: Detroit Edison Company and Utility Workers Union of America, Local 223, 1969-1972 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Code no.6014: Florida Power and Light Company and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, 1966-1973 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Code no.6064: Jersey Central Power and Light Company; New Jersey Power and Light Company and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Locals 327, 749, 1298, 1303, 1309, 1314, 1969-1973 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Code no.6087: Salt River Power District and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 266, 1963-1971 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Code no.6099: Salt River Valley Water Users' Association and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 266, 1965-1971 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Code no.6022: Minneapolis, Minnetonka, Normandale, and North Divisions of Northern States Power Company and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 160, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Code no.6026: Potomac Electric Power Company and Electric Utility Employees' Union, 1965-1972 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Code no.6030: Southern California Edison Company and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 47, 1969-1972 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Code no.591305: Boston Edison Company and Utility Workers Union of America, Local 387, 1961-1973 (Box 16, Folder 37)
  - Code no.6031: Tennessee Valley Authority and Salary Policy Employee Panel, 1955-1973 (Box 16, Folder 38)
  - Code no.6032: Tennessee Valley Authority and Tennessee Valley Trades and Labor Council, Hourly Employment, 1960-1964 (Box 16, Folder 39)
  - Code no.6033: Tennessee Valley Authority and Tennessee Valley Trades and Labor Council, Annual Employment, 1960-1964 (Box 16, Folder 40)
- Series IV: Industry Code #23, Construction
  - Code no.8421: South Florida Chapter of the Associated General Contractors of America, Inc., and Home Builders Association of South Florida and Carpenters' District Council of Miami, Florida and Vicinity, 1960-1969 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Code no.8441: Construction Industry Employers Association and International Hod Carriers, Building and Common Laborers Union of America, Local 210, 1960-1966 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Code no.8441: Construction Industry Employers Association and Laborers' International Union of North America Local 210, 1966- 1975 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Code no.8443: Construction Industry Employers Association and International Union of Operating Engineers, Locals 17, 17A, 17B, 1960- 1972 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Code no.8611: Glass, Glazing, and Mirror Contractors of Los Angeles and Vicinity and Glaziers, Glassworkers, and Glass Warehouse Workers Local 636 of Los Angeles, 1962-1970 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Code no.8617: Central Ohio Chapter of the Associated General Contractors of America, Inc. and United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America, Local 200, 1962-1972 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Code no.8632: Baltimore Builders Chapter of the Associated General Contractors of America and International Hod Carriers, Building and Common Laborers Union of America Locals 194, 1178, 1235, Laborers' District Council of Baltimore and Vicinity, 1962-1970 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Code no.8663: Allied Construction Industries of Delaware, Inc. and United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America, Local 626, 1965- 1971 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Code no.8672: Contracting Plumbers Association of Brooklyn and Queens, Inc. and United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipefitting Industry of the United States and Canada, Local 1, 1961-1975 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Code no.8673: Building Contractors' and Mason Builders' Association of Greater New York, Investing Builders Association and Elevator Constructors Union, Local 1, 1963-1972 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Code no.8675: Mechanical Contractors Association of New York, Inc. and United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry of the United States and Canada Local 638, Enterprise Association of Steam, Hot Water, Hydrau, 1963-1969 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Code no.8694: Associated General Contractors of Minnesota, Inc. and Laborers International Union of North America, Minnesota Laborers Locals, 1963-1972 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Code no.8720: Iron League of New York, Inc. and International Union of Operating Engineers, Locals 14, 15, 1963-1972 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Code no.8754: Associated Brick Mason Contractors of Greater New York, Inc. and Laborers' International Union of North America Local 66, General Building Laborers' Local Union, 1966-1972 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Code no.8767: Central Ohio Chapter of the Associated General Contractors of America, Inc. and the Network Contractors Association, et. al. and Laborers International Union of North America, Local 423, 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Code no.8410: Associated General Contractors of Massachusetts, Inc. and the Building Trades Employers' Association of the City of Boston and Boston Carpenters' District Council, 1960-1974 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Code no.8434: Builders Association of Chicago and Chicago District Council of Carpenters, 1957-1972 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Code no.8436: Carpenter Contractors' Association of Cleveland, Ohio, and Members of the Building Trades Employers' Association and Carpenters District Council - Cuyahoga Lake, Geauga, and Ashtabula Counties, 1956-1970 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Code no.8493: Eight Western States Area Agreement (Field Construction Work) and International Brotherhood of Boilermakers, Iron Ship Builders, Blacksmiths, Forgers and Helpers, 1959-1974 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Code no.8529: Institute of Electrical Contractors of the District of Columbia, Inc. and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 26, 1964-1973 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Code no.8547: Builders' Association of Chicago and Cement Masons, Rock Asphalt, and Composition Floor Finishers, Local 502, 1967- 1975 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Code no.8552: Lathing Contractors Association of Southern California, Inc. and Wood, Wire, and Metal Lathers International Union, Locals 42A, 81, 172, 252, and 366, 1959-1968 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Code no.8563: Rhode Island Chapter, Associated General Contractors of America, Inc. and United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America -Providence, Pawtucket, and Central Falls Carpenters, District Council, 1966-1975 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Code no.8567: Construction Employers Labor Relations Association of New York State, Inc. and United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America, Local 12, 1970-1973 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Code no.8599: Labor Relations Division of the Wisconsin Road Builders Association and International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America Joint Council 39, 1967-1973 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Code no.8599: Labor Relations Division of the Wisconsin Road Builders Association and Laborers International Union of North America, 1967- 1973 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Code no.8599: Labor Relations Division of the Wisconsin Road Builders Association and International Union of Operating Engineers, Local 139, 1967-1973 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Code no.8645: Rhode Island Chapter, Associated General Contractors of America, Inc. and International Hod Carriers, Building and Common Laborers Union of America, Local 271, 1960-1975 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Code no.8658: Allied Construction Employers Association, Inc. and Bridge, Structural and Ornamental Iron Workers' Local Union 8, 1962- 1974 (Box 4, Folder 14)